<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with php: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2016-10-13 08:41:00.001 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/php"/><entry><id>project-chaplin-032-point-release</id><title type="text">Project Chaplin 0.3.2 point release</title><updated>2016-10-13 08:41:00.001 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introducing the second point release for the 0.3 series of Project Chaplin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Chaplin is the first fully free software and open source video streaming service, installable locally or usable online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software is available through GitHub at &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/releases"&gt;https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/releases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New for&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;0.3.2&lt;/em&gt;: A demo server has been installed at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20170306223801/https://projectchaplin.com/login"&gt;https://projectchaplin.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) for those who wish to test without downloading anything! Please don't hit this server a lot, as it is only hosted on a small server, and is mainly for testing purposes. Please let me know (see below) if you notice any outstanding issues not covered in the issue tracker, and email me privately for any security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is always looking for new developers, designers and ideas people. Please contact "viablog032 att projectchaplin dott com" if you are looking for a new project to join. The list of new bugs, feature requests, etc is available at &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/issues"&gt;https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog (0.3 series)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;New in 0.3.2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fix the YouTube API/downloading problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New in 0.3.1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get and store access token for Vimeo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkify and space-ify descriptions Set cache lifetime to 30m to wipe old data from remote nodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New in 0.3:&lt;/strong&gt; Adds Docker support and includes a sample Docker file (with a Raspberry Pi release in the rpi branch). Logs and displays a link to the original YouTube link Adds fullscreen support to YouTube videos Makes the setup process more streamlined by starting daemons after setup is complete Adds Infinite loops a la infiniteyoutube.com Only imports Creative Commons videos from other services to avoid copyright issues Fixes YouTube API problems Shows correct licence on YouTube Removes old HTML5 requirements to add events to play videos and make them fullscreen - this now exists in all modern browsers UI improvements Splits the ORM into a new repository for other projects Faster loading through use of HTML5 AppCache (where enabled).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds Vimeo searching and importing support!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2016/10/project-chaplin-032-point-release"/></entry><entry><id>project-chaplin-031-released</id><title type="text">Project Chaplin 0.3.1 Released</title><updated>2016-09-16 14:23:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introducing the first bugfix release for the 0.3 release of Project Chaplin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Chaplin is the first fully free software and open source video streaming service, installable locally or usable online. It has been in development for a few years now, and has had significant development, and a new design added a couple of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software is available through GitHub at &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/releases"&gt;https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/releases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is always looking for new developers, designers and ideas people. Please contact "viablog031 att projectchaplin dott com" if you are looking for a new project to join. The list of new bugs, feature requests, etc is available at &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/issues"&gt;https://github.com/danwdart/projectchaplin/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changelog&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;New in 0.3.1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get and store access token for Vimeo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkify and space-ify descriptions Set cache lifetime to 30m to prevent old data from remote nodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New in 0.3:&lt;/strong&gt; Adds Docker support and includes a sample Docker file (with a Raspberry Pi release in the rpi branch). Logs and displays a link to the original YouTube link Adds fullscreen support to YouTube videos Makes the setup process more streamlined by starting daemons after setup is complete Adds Infinite loops a la infiniteyoutube.com Only imports Creative Commons videos from other services to avoid copyright issues Fixes YouTube API problems Shows correct licence on YouTube Removes old HTML5 requirements to add events to play videos and make them fullscreen - this now exists in all modern browsers UI improvements Splits the ORM into a new repository for other projects Faster loading through use of HTML5 AppCache (where enabled).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds Vimeo searching and importing support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New in Beta 2:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search now produces only CC-licenced YouTube videos&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2016/09/project-chaplin-031-released"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-web-desktop-alpha2-released</id><title type="text">Xenon Web Desktop Alpha2 Released</title><updated>2010-02-01 22:17:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The web desktop Xenon released version Alpha2 today. The release announcement from the website reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Changes from Alpha include many security fixes (including SQL injection), the addition of the Chatroom app, Pictures app, width autoscaling, new tab launching, easier installation and various visual tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please either use the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived), or ddownload to your server at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/xenon_alpha2.tar.bz2 (edit 2021: not archived). Please help by submitting bugs, patches, new apps, icons, etc to &lt;a href="mailto:xenon@dandart.co.uk" class="email"&gt;xenon@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a web desktop, which means that all your applications, work and settings are stored on the web. It can be run from any Internet-connected computer by browsing to the Xenon server or from your own server (in the case that you want a private instance, or want it installed into a netbook in the case where you do not have Internet connectivity). Eventually syncing support will be brought in which allows you to sync your settings and files to and from your local instance and the main server. Other features currently available include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio player (featuring HTML5 Vorbis audio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video player (featuring HTML5 Theora video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picture viewer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (including within Xenon and outgoing email)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chatroom (Public, open to all on the same instance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends application for social features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Files, to upload various types of file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallpaper switcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings syncing and importing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small footprint netbook/touchbook operating system to run on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try the system out for yourself, you can &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/"&gt;try the demo&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) or download the software at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/xenon_alpha2.tar.bz2 (edit 2021: not archived) to your server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send patches, icons, ideas, apps, et al to &lt;a href="mailto:xenon@dandart.co.uk"&gt;xenon@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project's website is at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/"&gt;https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) or a shorter version: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20091220083328/https://hackerlanes.com/"&gt;https://hackerlanes.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived)&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/02/xenon-web-desktop-alpha2-released"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-alpha-released</id><title type="text">Xenon Alpha released!</title><updated>2009-12-29 13:20:00.001 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An alpha version of the Xenon Desktop has been released. A description of the project follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a portable web or browser based desktop for netbooks and thin clients, designed to be the easiest desktop ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desktop includes a new GUI stepping away from traditional menus and is optimised for touchscreen and small devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system integrates social networking features and standard desktop features into one software package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being browser-based, it is cross platform and cross architecture. It is built on HTML5 and PHP components, and can be run on extremely low-powered machines, allowing for cheap distribution and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The backend can be run online (for users to access their data everywhere), on a personal LAN server, or on a small device, so the system can work offline, or if there are concerns about cloud storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An API is available at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/wiki/index.php/Developing_Apps (edit 2021: page not archived), so anyone can start developing apps to distribute in Xenon's upcoming App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project's homepage is located at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20091220083328/https://hackerlanes.com/"&gt;https://hackerlanes.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) including the online desktop, ready for instant testing and a download of the alpha image for your server. The actual small footprint OS that will run on netbooks will come later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage contributions to the project, in the form of code (the languages currently used are (X)HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and MySQL), art (eg icons, backgrounds, GUI concepts) or even just ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To send any requests or contributions, or to join the project, please email the head developer at &lt;a href="mailto:dan.dart@googlemail.com"&gt;dan.dart@googlemail.com&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/12/xenon-alpha-released"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-project-looking-for-helpers</id><title type="text">Xenon Project looking for helpers!</title><updated>2009-10-14 14:17:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started a project some time ago, which is for now called "Codename: Project Xenon".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a browser-based GUI designed to be implemented on netbooks. The difference between other netbook OSes and cloud systems is that not only can you test it online, it will also be installed on netbooks - which will update from the Web automatically, giving you updates, and ability to use it without being connected to the Internet due to a local web server instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will have a very small footprint - being built on very few programs, and so will run on very low-end systems, so it will bring life to your old computers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now looking for helpers to make this project a reality. If you are a designer or a programmer who can program using any combination of (X)HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP or MySQL, then we would like you to help us out. We are afraid pay is out of the question at the moment, until we start selling subscriptions to the web service, the budget is zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any ideas to help the project along, then please give us feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, simply email: &lt;a href="mailto:dan.dart@googlemail.com"&gt;dan.dart@googlemail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visit the main website of the project, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) To try out the web based desktop for yourself, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100224082039/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/desktop"&gt;Try The Desktop&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived partially). Please note that it is nowhere near finished at the moment. To view the SDK and programming procedures to help you, click here: Xenon SDK at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/wiki/index.php/Developing_Apps (edit 2021: not archived)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and have a good day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/10/xenon-project-looking-for-helpers"/></entry></feed>