<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with web: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2010-09-10 10:55:00.001 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/web"/><entry><id>bibud-alpha-51-released</id><title type="text">Bibud Alpha 5.1 released</title><updated>2010-09-10 10:55:00.001 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bibud, the open source social web desktop released its Alpha 5.1 version today, including many design changes and bigfixes, finally integrating links to git and a bugtracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the new features to Alpha 5.1 were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homepage improvements Facebook support in Chatroom Media sharing initial demo support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always you can find Bibud at &lt;a href="https://bibud.com/"&gt;https://bibud.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/09/bibud-alpha-51-released"/></entry><entry><id>bibud-social-web-desktop-alpha5</id><title type="text">Bibud Social Web Desktop Alpha5 Released</title><updated>2010-08-01 19:01:00.001 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The fifth bugfix update to the Bibud web desktop was released yesterday, and includes easier application installations, a better SDK, a clearer layout, better window management and removal of application previews not relevant to the web demo at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've not come across Bibud before, it is a desktop and window manager including and designed to contain several web-based applications that work together to make your computer experience easier. It is designed to run on desktop, laptop or netbook computers, and with a low footprint, is designed to work well on the lowest specification computers available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bibud is the name of the entire project, but a demo of what the desktop will look like is available to demo on the web at &lt;a href="https://bibud.com" class="uri"&gt;https://bibud.com&lt;/a&gt; - later on it will come preinstalled inaide a GNU/Linux distribution enabling computers to connect and share data with each other in an as easy way as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technologies in use in Bibud are HTML5 for the audio and video elements, AJAX for most of the desktop, and the backends are programmed in PHP and MySQL, enabling any user with the LAMP stack installed (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) to easily download and install the software. The git repository is available on &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/Bibud/"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: changed organisation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the following applications are available to try out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio, Video, Pictures (media viewing applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chatroom (an irc-esque chatroom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Blog application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microblog (submit posts to Twitter, identi.ca, status.net, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Files (a file upload manager)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends (to keep track of contacts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background (to change desktop wallpaper)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Info (to change user's passwords, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features just around the corner are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note taking applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra goodies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try out the alpha 5 prerelease of the desktop by visiting &lt;a href="https://bibud.com/"&gt;https://bibud.com&lt;/a&gt; in your HTML5-compliant web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bibud project are looking for volunteers to help with the project, code contributions, artwork, designs, proof-of-concepts and even just ideas are welcome, and may well be accepted into the official project distribution. If you have anything to contribute, please email the project leader at &lt;a href="mailto:bibud@dandart.co.uk" class="email"&gt;bibud@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. The Bibud project is licensed under a MIT-style license.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/08/bibud-social-web-desktop-alpha5"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-web-desktop-alpha2-released</id><title type="text">Xenon Web Desktop Alpha2 Released</title><updated>2010-02-01 22:17:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The web desktop Xenon released version Alpha2 today. The release announcement from the website reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Changes from Alpha include many security fixes (including SQL injection), the addition of the Chatroom app, Pictures app, width autoscaling, new tab launching, easier installation and various visual tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please either use the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived), or ddownload to your server at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/xenon_alpha2.tar.bz2 (edit 2021: not archived). Please help by submitting bugs, patches, new apps, icons, etc to &lt;a href="mailto:xenon@dandart.co.uk" class="email"&gt;xenon@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a web desktop, which means that all your applications, work and settings are stored on the web. It can be run from any Internet-connected computer by browsing to the Xenon server or from your own server (in the case that you want a private instance, or want it installed into a netbook in the case where you do not have Internet connectivity). Eventually syncing support will be brought in which allows you to sync your settings and files to and from your local instance and the main server. Other features currently available include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio player (featuring HTML5 Vorbis audio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video player (featuring HTML5 Theora video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picture viewer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email (including within Xenon and outgoing email)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chatroom (Public, open to all on the same instance)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friends application for social features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Files, to upload various types of file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wallpaper switcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upcoming features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings syncing and importing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small footprint netbook/touchbook operating system to run on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try the system out for yourself, you can &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/"&gt;try the demo&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) or download the software at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/xenon_alpha2.tar.bz2 (edit 2021: not archived) to your server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send patches, icons, ideas, apps, et al to &lt;a href="mailto:xenon@dandart.co.uk"&gt;xenon@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project's website is at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/"&gt;https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) or a shorter version: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20091220083328/http://hackerlanes.com/"&gt;https://hackerlanes.com&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived)&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/02/xenon-web-desktop-alpha2-released"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-project-looking-for-helpers</id><title type="text">Xenon Project looking for helpers!</title><updated>2009-10-14 14:17:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started a project some time ago, which is for now called "Codename: Project Xenon".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a browser-based GUI designed to be implemented on netbooks. The difference between other netbook OSes and cloud systems is that not only can you test it online, it will also be installed on netbooks - which will update from the Web automatically, giving you updates, and ability to use it without being connected to the Internet due to a local web server instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will have a very small footprint - being built on very few programs, and so will run on very low-end systems, so it will bring life to your old computers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now looking for helpers to make this project a reality. If you are a designer or a programmer who can program using any combination of (X)HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP or MySQL, then we would like you to help us out. We are afraid pay is out of the question at the moment, until we start selling subscriptions to the web service, the budget is zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any ideas to help the project along, then please give us feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, simply email: &lt;a href="mailto:dan.dart@googlemail.com"&gt;dan.dart@googlemail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visit the main website of the project, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) To try out the web based desktop for yourself, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100224082039/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/desktop"&gt;Try The Desktop&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived partially). Please note that it is nowhere near finished at the moment. To view the SDK and programming procedures to help you, click here: Xenon SDK at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/wiki/index.php/Developing_Apps (edit 2021: not archived)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and have a good day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/10/xenon-project-looking-for-helpers"/></entry></feed>