<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with l: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2011-03-21 23:40:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/l"/><entry><id>playcom-compromised-names-and-emails</id><title type="text">Play.com compromised, names and emails taken</title><updated>2011-03-21 23:40:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The popular UK online shop Play.com has reportedly been compromised, revealing its database of usernames and email addresses of its customers to its attackers. An email appearing to be from play.com to its customers reads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Customer,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email Security Message&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are emailing all our customers to let you know that a company that handles part of our marketing communications has had a security breach. Unfortunately this has meant that some customer names and email addresses may have been compromised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take privacy and security very seriously and ensure all sensitive customer data is protected. Please be assured this issue has occurred outside of Play.com and no other personal customer information has been involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be assured we have taken every step to ensure this doesn’t happen again and accept our apologies for any inconvenience this may have caused some of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customer Advice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do be vigilant with your email and personal information when using the internet. At Play.com we will never ask you for information such as passwords, bank account details or credit card numbers. If you receive anything suspicious in your email, please do not click on any links and forward the email on to &lt;a href="mailto:privacy@play.com" class="email"&gt;privacy@play.com&lt;/a&gt; for us to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for continuing to shop at Play.com and we look forward to serving you in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Play.com Customer Service Team&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2011/03/playcom-compromised-names-and-emails"/></entry></feed>