<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with cabal: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2024-12-21 22:44:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/cabal"/><entry><id>everything-i-maintain-now-built-with-ghc-910</id><title type="text">Everything I maintain now built with GHC 9.10</title><updated>2024-12-21 22:44:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! All executable and library targets I build in Haskell are now built with GHC 9.10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, GHCJS et al are still using GHC 8.10 for now, but the important point is that I've finally upgraded my last two programs from being stuck at GHC 9.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on the way to building with GHC 9.12... once everything supports it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch this space...&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2024/12/everything-i-maintain-now-built-with-ghc-910"/></entry><entry><id>this-blog-now-built-with-ghc-94</id><title type="text">This blog now built with GHC 9.4</title><updated>2022-10-10 01:08:02 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Double huzzah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website has now been successfully built with GHC 9.4!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fewer bug reports and overrides to support it, but you can always check the website sources: &lt;a href="https://github.com/danwdart/websites.git" class="uri"&gt;https://github.com/danwdart/websites.git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very good job to you, Haskell and GHC maintainers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2022/10/this-blog-now-built-with-ghc-94"/></entry><entry><id>this-blog-now-built-with-ghc-92</id><title type="text">This blog now built with GHC 9.2</title><updated>2022-03-24 19:13:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Huzzah! This blog and set of websites has finally been built using the new latest version of GHC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst it's not doing anything that special, it marks the ability to use this version to compile all its dependencies, which have had to be modified, bug-reported and pull-requested to get it all to work, and worked around when these have not been responded to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've forked a bunch of my dependencies to get them to work, and am very happy that I'm free to update the dependencies I use to work for my needs, and that's really the power of free/libre open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually quite surprised that the release cycle of GHC itself seems so quick, and it's the main libraries that many people use that lag behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TTFN!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2022/03/this-blog-now-built-with-ghc-92"/></entry></feed>