<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with dns: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2025-12-11 00:33:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/dns"/><entry><id>sites-still-use-without-ipv6</id><title type="text">Sites I use still without IPv6</title><updated>2025-12-11 00:33:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I went over &lt;a href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2025/03/behind-times-sites-still-without-ipv6-2025/"&gt;a list of some of the world's top websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought this might not be particularly accurate for an actual list of websites one person would use, so I made a small bash script to scrape the websites in my bookmarks (which is synced across phone and desktop, so a good mix of websites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I haven't sorted it by popularity but I wouldn't imagine that it would be too hard to use one of many site ranking tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I would go over some of the bigger ones and name and shame and then provide a percentage point for websites which &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; have not gotten themselves an IPv6 address after becoming a draft standard 27 years ago, having a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_IPv6_Day_and_World_IPv6_Launch_Day"&gt;scheduled global adoption date 13 years ago&lt;/a&gt; and becoming an Internet Standard &lt;em&gt;eight years ago&lt;/em&gt;, this is an ancient thing that most public wifi access points I join have never heard of and only exists as far as I can see in corporate offices and private homes, despite it being one of the standards everything must have already adopted years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of a total of &lt;em&gt;4,617 registered domain names&lt;/em&gt; which resolve, I have bookmarked over the last bunch of years, only &lt;em&gt;2,108 had an IPv6 address&lt;/em&gt; (only &lt;em&gt;46%&lt;/em&gt;!) which is frankly shocking, leaving the remaining &lt;em&gt;2,509 IPv4-only&lt;/em&gt; which will be inaccessible to many new setups if they do not upgrade by the time that internet service providers are forced to go IPv6-only. Note that I didn't check the actual availability, this is purely DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few notable, shocking examples of websites that still have not updated are ProtonVPN, Samsung, AllenAI, Amazon, Pokémon, Arxiv, Nextdoor, CanIUse, Discord, Uber, Mozilla, Imgur, MathsJam, Meetup, Ebay, Sky and Quora along with many gaming, e-commerce, social media, comparator, food and parcel delivery, video hosting, health, government and money handling websites along with many credit agencies, news publications, mobile providers, shops and petition sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite shocking, as much of a stuck record that it makes me sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time in the internet infrastructure series, with the recent rise of downtimes in huge CDNs, how about "how many of my bookmarks are powered by AWS and Cloudflare"?&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2025/12/sites-still-use-without-ipv6"/></entry><entry><id>i-use-opennic-for-dns-its-cool-independent-custom</id><title type="text">I use OpenNIC for DNS, it's cool, independent and custom</title><updated>2025-03-14 18:30:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wish you could register domain names for free, with cool TLDs? Well... you can, in a private, democratic community namespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a set of community-maintained DNS servers, some of which run with DoH, DoT, DNSSEC and claim to not log, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's so good about that? Doesn't everybody do that? What's the niche, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The niche here is a set of custom, OpenNIC-only TLDs you can register and maintain for free, which is kind of neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about TLS, though? How do you get certificates for it? Surely if other DNS providers don't understand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what you can do is that you can use custom certificates. Of course, this means you'll need to do one of two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and self-sign your own certificate This means that everybody will have to trust you and pass through the yellow screens when visiting your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and run your own certificate authority on your own computer This means that you, and only you, will not have to face the yellow screens, and it's kind of useful. It still protects against man-in-the-middle attacks, because you'll have to click through otherwise signed certificates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.opennic.org/opennic/tls"&gt;Import a "special" root certificate from the wiki&lt;/a&gt;, then run ACME against their server, specifically. This means you can share the authority between users of the authority, and that you'll have to trust the authority, but otherwise no yellow screens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice. Anything else you can do with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's always volunteering to run a DNS server or providing translations if you're multilingual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's pretty cool. How do I get started?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply visit &lt;a href="https://opennic.org/"&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;. You'll find information about what DNS servers to add that are closest to you, and you can decide what kind of domains you wish to register. There are some pretty gnarly ones available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ta-ta!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2025/03/i-use-opennic-for-dns-its-cool-independent-custom"/></entry><entry><id>facebook-being-down-killed-adguard</id><title type="text">Facebook being down killed AdGuard</title><updated>2021-10-08 16:37:31 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tbh Facebook being down the other day did have one knock-on effect for me who doesn’t use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adguard DNS got quite a pummeling from folks trying to access Facebook and their entire DNS effectively got DDoSed, leaving nothing getting resolved for a good while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile I over here killed my own internet by disabling DNS on my router for days thinking it would revert to default. Was very confusing as I had adguard hardcoded on my PC as well, but not my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week went like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone: "No internet".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me on my PC: "Huh? But it’s working! See?"&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2021/10/facebook-being-down-killed-adguard"/></entry></feed>