<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with azure: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2008-10-28 16:08:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/azure"/><entry><id>cloud-os</id><title type="text">Cloud OS</title><updated>2008-10-28 16:08:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've noticed that a lot of companies have decided the Cloud (applications on the Internet) is the future. For me, I use a fair few to the extent that I don't use OpenOffice any more, just Google Apps. What particularly provoked me is that big companies are now doing it the whole hog. (see www.linux.com/feed/151604 (edit 2021: sorry, page not archived)) So I've decided to make one. It should be: Easy to use Intuitive Aesthetically pleasing Not be anything like today's GUIs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've gathered a few people to help me with this big task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From another blog, "5 things I wish Linux had" at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20090619065522/http://www.daniweb.com/blogs/entry3288.html" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20090619065522/http://www.daniweb.com/blogs/entry3288.html&lt;/a&gt; (edit: archived) gave me inspiration so I contacted the author to ask him for help with ideas for this OS. He has since made a few more blogs about what Linux needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This person's blog is now located at: &lt;a href="https://thefrugalnetworker.wordpress.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://thefrugalnetworker.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another blog, "10 Features Ubuntu Should Implement" at &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20120226075352/http://www.kumailht.com/blog/linux/10-features-ubuntu-should-implement/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20120226075352/http://www.kumailht.com/blog/linux/10-features-ubuntu-should-implement/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: now archived but imagegave me yet more inspiration of what to include in my custom made cloud OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like anyone and everyone to help make this Cloud system by any means possible, be that advertising, programming, or graphics so please contact me on (&lt;a href="mailto:cloudos@dandart.co.uk" class="email"&gt;cloudos@dandart.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;) (edit 2021: change email) if you would like to be involved in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2008/10/cloud-os"/></entry></feed>