<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with hardware: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2010-01-24 14:52:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/hardware"/><entry><id>linuxs-hardware-support</id><title type="text">Linux's Hardware Support</title><updated>2010-01-24 14:52:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been hearing a lot about "Linux needs to master .... to beat Windows". I'll now show you how that's completely false, and how it already has beaten it, by talking about hardware support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux has been proved to have the best hardware support around - see &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210224170701/https://howsoftwareisbuilt.com/2009/11/18/interview-with-greg-kroah-hartman-linux-kernel-devmaintainer/"&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) with Greg KH who's a kernel dev to see in-depth information. Linux had most support for hardware first, including: * 64 bit * USB 3.0 * Core i7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many more. Conversely, it's easy to install the hardware on Linux. In windows for instance, half the time your hardware doesn't work because you downloaded a dodgy driver, or you have to install it off a CD, or it could even be the case that it bluescreens because the driver hasn't been verified by whoever. Fair enough, that hardly ever happens anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The misconception that a lot of hardware doesn't work on Linux isn't because it doesn't, it does, but because quite often your distribution of choice doesn't ship with the correct userspace tools - e.g. a webcam viewer, a scanning program, an iPod syncer. It's not the actual Linux kernel that's at fault here, it's that the distribution vendors don't include software to manage and access your device. What we need here is a project that either includes everything or says "I see you've inserted a scanner, but you don't have a scanning application. Want me to install one for you?". I have seen openSUSE do this for me before, but Ubuntu sadly lacks this capability, which is the distro that most users allegedly use, so it needs it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is, every piece of hardware I've put into my Linux box has been detected and set up by Linux, but I have had to install a webcam viewer, scanning application and TV viewer. Perhaps it's time for userspace tools to improve themselves and be as good as the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/01/linuxs-hardware-support"/></entry><entry><id>xenon-project-looking-for-helpers</id><title type="text">Xenon Project looking for helpers!</title><updated>2009-10-14 14:17:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started a project some time ago, which is for now called "Codename: Project Xenon".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xenon is a browser-based GUI designed to be implemented on netbooks. The difference between other netbook OSes and cloud systems is that not only can you test it online, it will also be installed on netbooks - which will update from the Web automatically, giving you updates, and ability to use it without being connected to the Internet due to a local web server instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will have a very small footprint - being built on very few programs, and so will run on very low-end systems, so it will bring life to your old computers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now looking for helpers to make this project a reality. If you are a designer or a programmer who can program using any combination of (X)HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP or MySQL, then we would like you to help us out. We are afraid pay is out of the question at the moment, until we start selling subscriptions to the web service, the budget is zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any ideas to help the project along, then please give us feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, simply email: &lt;a href="mailto:dan.dart@googlemail.com"&gt;dan.dart@googlemail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To visit the main website of the project, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) To try out the web based desktop for yourself, click here: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100224082039/https://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/desktop"&gt;Try The Desktop&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived partially). Please note that it is nowhere near finished at the moment. To view the SDK and programming procedures to help you, click here: Xenon SDK at xenon.kevinghadyani.com/wiki/index.php/Developing_Apps (edit 2021: not archived)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and have a good day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/10/xenon-project-looking-for-helpers"/></entry><entry><id>how-to-conquer-desktop</id><title type="text">How to Conquer the Desktop</title><updated>2009-08-19 19:28:00.001 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does Sturmbahnfahrer mean? And who would have guessed the meaning of Stormbaan Coureur? They are different names for the same software: "a simulated obstacle course for automobiles".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now grab someone off the street and ask them what Linux means. No? A "command-line" operating system is all you'll get from a lot of people. Most people who have used Linux before the year 2000 have had some sort of problem, due to usability, and it has put them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, ask them what Windows means. Sure, it's an English word and English is fast becoming the language of choice. It has two meanings: "A piece of glass" or "What my computer always says first". People don't know anything about operating systems. What your computer has is what it will have forever, is most people's opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change systems then is a frightening step to many and many won't be clever enough to understand the concept that something will "exist outside of Windows".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wubi meanwhile (a program to install Ubuntu "inside" Windows) will just confuse people even more. If they understand Ubuntu is another program, they won't get why they can't just use their own programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don't care about how free or open their system is. They'll buy Windows 7 because they'll probably hate Vista or be forced into it. We had a little legroom while Vista was out since Windows users started looking around for something different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, people fear change. They won't move away from what they're used to even if it is fundamentally broken or flawed or just keeps crashing. The only way to wrench people away is to add more small Linux-based devices to the market. Netbooks are doing pretty well in this area. Due to people not recognising it as a computer (or a laptop) people will be more open to what is on it. The same happened with the iPhone. The software is different, yes, but the hardware is also different, so people feel that they can accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change people with an open mind (a lot of users are switching already) we need to follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STANDARDISE!! This is the most confusing aspect. Have ONE standard distro, call it something cool and DON'T mention Linux. Have ONE standard Desktop Environment. Everyone knows how to use it, it's all the same.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have ONE Package manager. That means ONE way of installing. It won't break if more people work on it. Have packages downloadable in a format inclusive of all the libraries. Also have an add and remove panel. Repositories are cool. They have made our software secure. Let's have ONE repository containing only GUI end user applications, named after their use (Image Editor not GIMP) and have essential packages built into the system. No library packages, no dependencies, Just download Image Editor and it works. Perhaps like Acorn or Mac OS, in which you drag and drop the program to your desktop and it works. If duplicate libraries from packages exist, keep the newer. If packages break, the library has dropped support for something, so don't drop it! If a console app exists now, make a standard frontend for configuring it. E.g. Web server package (inAdvanced section) installs Apache AND a STANDARD frontend, All its libraries are there in the package. One package file to install for Web server. One to install for File Server. And so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard packages. Have ONE text editor. If it lacks features from others, add them. Have a beginner and advanced mode. Etc. Call them "Text Editor" not "nano" or "kate" or "gedit". What the hell are those?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertising. Advertise like you've never advertise before! PRODUCT! And why you should buy it! It's cool! Let's all get on this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STABLE! If things can break, fix them BEFORE releasing. Ubuntu releases broken products (look at 8.10). Debian delays but releases when finished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HARDWARE! My brother's iPod Nano doesn't work in Linux straight away. This is one thing that will leave people ditching Linux. My 3D games I downloaded don't work. I don't want to have to bother with nVidia drivers. My camera doesn't get picked up. I can't sync to my MTP media player out of the box. Etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Command Line. No one should EVER have to type anything into a console. It's simple user-friendliness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's all work on this and soon we'll have a user friendly system, easy to use, ready for the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is an ongoing project to conquer this challenge. Its codename is Xenon and it tries to do all this in the browser. It can be used on all devices and will be installed on small devices. To catch up with development or contribute, please visit: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/" class="uri"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20100107134808/http://xenon.kevinghadyani.com/&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived)&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/08/how-to-conquer-desktop"/></entry></feed>