<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Posts tagged with ubuntu: JolHarg: Software and Technology Blog</title><id>https://blog.jolharg.com/atom.xml</id><updated>2010-01-24 14:52:00 UTC</updated><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/tag/ubuntu"/><entry><id>linuxs-hardware-support</id><title type="text">Linux's Hardware Support</title><updated>2010-01-24 14:52:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I've been hearing a lot about "Linux needs to master .... to beat Windows". I'll now show you how that's completely false, and how it already has beaten it, by talking about hardware support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux has been proved to have the best hardware support around - see &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210224170701/https://howsoftwareisbuilt.com/2009/11/18/interview-with-greg-kroah-hartman-linux-kernel-devmaintainer/"&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived) with Greg KH who's a kernel dev to see in-depth information. Linux had most support for hardware first, including: * 64 bit * USB 3.0 * Core i7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many more. Conversely, it's easy to install the hardware on Linux. In windows for instance, half the time your hardware doesn't work because you downloaded a dodgy driver, or you have to install it off a CD, or it could even be the case that it bluescreens because the driver hasn't been verified by whoever. Fair enough, that hardly ever happens anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The misconception that a lot of hardware doesn't work on Linux isn't because it doesn't, it does, but because quite often your distribution of choice doesn't ship with the correct userspace tools - e.g. a webcam viewer, a scanning program, an iPod syncer. It's not the actual Linux kernel that's at fault here, it's that the distribution vendors don't include software to manage and access your device. What we need here is a project that either includes everything or says "I see you've inserted a scanner, but you don't have a scanning application. Want me to install one for you?". I have seen openSUSE do this for me before, but Ubuntu sadly lacks this capability, which is the distro that most users allegedly use, so it needs it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is, every piece of hardware I've put into my Linux box has been detected and set up by Linux, but I have had to install a webcam viewer, scanning application and TV viewer. Perhaps it's time for userspace tools to improve themselves and be as good as the kernel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2010/01/linuxs-hardware-support"/></entry><entry><id>sync-iphoneipod-touch-3g-in-ubuntu</id><title type="text">Sync iPhone/iPod Touch 3G in Ubuntu</title><updated>2009-11-29 03:47:00 UTC</updated><author><name>Dan Dart</name></author><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been trying very hard to get iPhone and iPod Touch syncing to work correctly in Linux. Some have been doing a FUSE filesystem (which accesses the iPod) and some the database and syncing. Remember this is pre-alpha quality, but I found it synced my tunes nicely from Linux. But due to the database version being old (but quite good enough for the iPod), iTunes does not play nice with it - and will just resync the tracks and may delete them. Also the iPod must have been previosly initialised with a version of iTunes. If you cannot acquire it, or it will not run, contact teuf on #gtkpod in irc.freenode.net. You have been warned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mounting support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, grab iFuse: Add the following lines to /etc/apt/sources.list as root:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deb &lt;a href="http://ppa.launchpad.net/jonabeck/ppa/ubuntu" class="uri"&gt;http://ppa.launchpad.net/jonabeck/ppa/ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; intrepid main deb-src &lt;a href="http://ppa.launchpad.net/jonabeck/ppa/ubuntu" class="uri"&gt;http://ppa.launchpad.net/jonabeck/ppa/ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; intrepid main&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-key adv --recv-keys --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com F0876AC9 sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install ifuse ifuse-dev&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should install support for reading and writing files. Create a mount point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo mkdir /media/ipodt/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add yourself to the fuse group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo useradd -G fuse [your_user_name]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To allow normal users to mount the FUSE filesystems, edit /etc/fuse.conf and uncomment the line (remove the hash from the start of it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;\#user_allow_other&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log out and back in again, or spawn a new login shell. Mount the FUSE filesystem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ifuse /media/ipodt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see that your iPod should be mounted as yourself. You should be able to find the tracks and play them from the computer. They are oddly named and located in iTunes_Control/Music .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syncing support&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To properly sync music (well I say properly), you need to install a special branch of libgpod. You'll need to get it from git. WARNING! THIS WILL OVERWRITE YOUR EXISTING LIBGPOD! Be careful. First install development libraries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get install git-core build-essential cmake autoconf automake libtool intltool gtk-doc-tools libsqlite3-dev zlib1g-dev&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get teuf's sandbox repository branch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git clone &lt;a href="git://gitorious.org/~teuf/libgpod/teuf-sandbox.git" class="uri"&gt;git://gitorious.org/~teuf/libgpod/teuf-sandbox.git&lt;/a&gt; cd teuf-sandbox git checkout origin/iphone30 CFLAGS="-g -O0" sh autogen.sh --prefix=/usr make sudo make install&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;libgpod should now be installed, if all goes to plan. Create control directories and files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;mkdir /media/ipodt/iTunes_Control/Device&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get the uuid of your device:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lsusb -v | grep -i iSerial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be the one that's 40 characters long. From the same teuf-sandbox directory, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tools/ipod-read-sysinfo-extended /media/ipodt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check that a file exists. Do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cat /media/ipodt/iTunes_Control/Device/SysInfoExtended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should spew XML at you. Now, install your syncing program of choice. I chose gtkpod because it works for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo apt-get instal gtkpod&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program should pick up the device and ask which model it is. There should be your device listed at the bottom (you may have to scroll). Choose it and let it do its thing, and initialise your iPod. Check a file has been created:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ls /media/ipodt/iTunes_Control/Device&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get nothing, there's a problem. Go ask teuf. If you get that filename returned. all is well. You are able to sync, save files and update the database. Bear in mind that it saves an older version of the database, so if you go to iTunes and back, it will update tracks and the database, but they should still be readable in Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this has been helpful to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some helpful references if you get stuck: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20100211151037/http://matt.colyer.name:80/projects/iphone-linux/?title=Main_Page"&gt;iFuse&lt;/a&gt; (edit 2021: archived, also moved project to &lt;a href="https://libimobiledevice.org/" class="uri"&gt;https://libimobiledevice.org/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href="https://marcansoft.com/blog/2009/10/iphone-syncing-on-linux-part-2/"&gt;iPod Syncing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://blog.jolharg.com/post/2009/11/sync-iphoneipod-touch-3g-in-ubuntu"/></entry></feed>